A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 FA739F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Governmental policies promoting management of wildlife and wildlife-based recreation on American Indian reservations: a report to the following tribes: Crow, Flathead, Hualapai, Northern Cheyenne, Rosebud Sioux, San Carlos Apache, White Mountain Apache (Reports 016031), 1989 (Box 820, Reel R-9314)
  Wildlife management -- United States; Indian reservations -- United States
- The Crow tribal government and economic development: A report to the Crow Tribe of Montana (Reports 016032), 1988 (Box 820, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series / (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);[88-12]
  Crow Indians -- Politics and government; Crow Indians -- Economic conditions; Indians of North America -- Politics and government; Indians of North America -- Economic conditions
- Agricultural income analysis for the Yakima Reservation: Report to the Yakima Tribal Council (Reports 016033), 1988 (Box 820, Reel R-9314)
  Report on agricultural income values on the Yakima Reservation in the state of Washington, with an analysis of crops, cattle and idle land.
  Yakima Indians; Confederated Tribes and Bands of the Yakama Indian Nation of the Yakama Reservation
- Are Indians getting a good deal?: A study of Bureau of Indian Affairs forest management (Reports 016034), 1989 (Box 820, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series / Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development;89-3
  Forest management -- United States; Indians of North America -- Economic conditions; Indian reservations -- United States
- Use of computer modeling in forest management on the Flathead Reservation, Montana: Report to Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes of the Flathead Reservation, Montana (Reports 016035), 1988 (Box 820, Reel R-9314)
  Report on the use of computer software to predict management needs for forest lands on the Salish and Kootenai Reservations of Montana.
  Forests and forestry -- Measurement -- Computer programs; Indian reservations
- Factors determining success and/or failure for economic development projects on Indian reservations in Canada (Reports 016036), 1988 (Box 820, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series / Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development
  Indian reservations -- Canada; Indian business enterprises -- Canada; Indians of North America -- Economic conditions
- Navajo forest products industries: establishing an economic development corporation: a report to the Navajo forest products industries (Reports 016037), 1989 (Box 820, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);89-09.
  Navajo Indians -- Economic conditions; Indians of North America -- Southwest, New -- Economic conditions; Forest products industry -- United States
- An analysis of the proposed Yellowtail Afterbay Dam hydroelectricity plant on the Bighorn River in Montana: a report to the Crow Tribe of Montana (Reports 016038), 1987 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);87-2.
  Crow Indians -- Economic conditions; Indians of North America -- Economic conditions; Hydroelectric power plants -- Economic aspects -- Montana
- The redefinition of property rights in American Indian reservations: a comparative analysis of native American economic development (Reports 016039), 1987 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Discussion paper series (John F. Kennedy School of Government. Energy and Environmental Policy Center);E-87-05.
  Indians of North America -- Indian reservations; Indians of North America -- Economic conditions; Indians of North America -- Government policy -- 1934; Indians of North America -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Indians of North America -- Civil rights
- Developing a management plan for Crow tribal wildlife resources: A report to the Crow tribe of Montana, 1987/ Kim Nead and Denise Toussaint (Reports 016040) (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  THe President and Fellows of Harvard College
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);87-4.
  Wildlife management -- Montana; Crow Indians -- Economic conditions
- Negotiating the best possible coal contract: Report to the Crow Tribe of Montana (Reports 016041), 1987 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Paper drafted to prepare the Crow Tribe for coal royalty contract arbitration with Westmoreland Resources, Inc.
  Discussion paper series (John F. Kennedy School of Government. Energy and Environmental Policy Center)
  Crow Indians; Coal mines and mining -- Montana -- Legal status, laws, etc.
- A prototypical development corporation for American Indian tribes (Reports 016042), 1988 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  'The Crow Indian Tribe of Montana faces a great challenge in overcoming the social ills that accompany its 85% unemployment rate and near absolute dependence on public assistance programs... Part of the strategy for developing the economy is to design an
  Indians of North America -- Economic conditions; Crow Indians -- Economic conditions; Community development corporations
- Encouraging entrepreneurship on the San Carlos Apache Reservation: a report to the San Carlos Apache tribe (Reports 016043), 1988 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);88-6.
  Entrepreneurship -- United States; Indian business enterprises -- United States; Indians of North America -- Economic conditions; Apache Indians -- Economic conditions
- Economic development: The Rosebud Sioux Indian Tribe; A report to the Rosebud Sioux Tribe (Reports 016044), 1988 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);88-08.
  Dakota Indians -- Economic conditions; Dakota Indians -- Politics and government; Rosebud Indian Reservation (S.D.)
- Evaluation of reservation-based loan programs: report to First Nations Financial Project (Reports 016045), 1988 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);88-9.
  Indians of North America -- Financial affairs
- Developing an agenda for the Tokatakiya Research Institute at the Oglala Lakota College: report to the Oglala Lakota College, Pine Ridge Sioux Tribe (Reports 016046), 1988 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  'The recommended activities the Institute should consider undertaking include the following: 1. Setting up an Advisory Board 2. Securing funding from foundations and corporations and formalizing contractual arrangement 3. Increasing human and physical res
  Indians of North America -- Education -- South Dakota -- Pine Ridge Indian Reservation (S.D.)
- Completing the White Mountain Apache Tribal Museum and Culture Center: a report to the White Mountain Apache Tribe (Reports 016047), 1988 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);88-10.
- Apache cattle: The reservation as marketplace, a sale yard feasibility study: A report to the San Carlos Apache Tribe (Reports 016048), 1988 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);89-11.
  Cattle trade -- Arizona; Indian business enterprises
- Pathways from poverty: development and institution-building on American Indian reservations (Reports 016049), 1989 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  'For the past year and a half the Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development has been engaged in systematic research on the conditions under which self-determined economic development can be successful on American Indian reservations. This pa
  The President and Fellows of Hervard College
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);89-5.
  Indians of North America -- Economic conditions; Indians of North America -- Politics and government; Indians of North America -- Indian reservations
- The tribal judiciary: A primer for policy development: a report to the following tribes: Pascua Yaqui, Gila River, Hopi, Navajo, White Mountain Apache, San Carlos Apache, and Tohono O'odham (Reports 016050), 1989 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  'This paper examines tribal judiciaries, their role in tribal governments, and the ways in which the different judicial systems can serve tribal purposes. The main body of the paper contains discussion of tribal choices, while the appendices include chart
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);89-6.
  Indians of North America -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Justice, Administration of; Indian courts
- When things go wrong: disciplinary policies for tribal departments: a report to the Hualapai Indian tribe of Arizona, 1989; by Marc Koehler. (Reports 016051) (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development);89-07.
  Hualapai Indians -- Politics and government; Indians of North America -- Arizona; Justice, Administration of
- Recommendations for the establishment of the Cherokee Community Loan Fund Microenterprise Project (Reports 016052), 1989 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Project report series / (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development)
  Microfinance; Indians of North America -- Economic conditions
- Organizational design proposal for tribal economic development planning and management: Report to the Northern Cheyenne Tribe (Reports 016053), 1989 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  [Project report series (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development) ]
  Indian reservations -- Economic conditions; Charters -- Law and legislation
- Economic welfare in Indian country: a consideration of history 1868-1968 (Reports 016054), 1989 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  Indians of North America -- Economic conditions; Welfare economics
- Tohono O'Odham: a tribal court system model (Reports 016055), 1989 (Box 821, Reel R-9314)
  'An analysis of the practical, philosophical and problematic aspects of tribal court systems, using the Tohono O'odham judiciary as a model.' (p. 2)
  Tohono O'odham Indians -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Justice, Administration of; Indian courts
- Reform measures for the Oglala Sioux tribal government: Report to the Oglala Sioux tribe (Reports 016056), 1989 (Box 821, Reel R-9315)
  Study examines structural and administrative deficiencies within the Oglala Sioux tribal government and suggests measures to achieve a clearer delineation of responsibilities, enhance program management, and create a more stable and consistent governing e
  Report to the Oglala Sioux Tribe: Project report series Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development
  Indians of North America -- Politics and government; Tribal government; Indian reservations
- Reform of criminal justice administration and protecting the rights of vulnerable groups (POM) (Reports 016057), 2002 (Box 821, Reel R-9315)
  INITIATIVES: Reform of Criminal Justice Administration, and Protecting the Rights of Vulnerable Groups. "The first initiative will...support developing increased protections for criminal defendants' human rights including freedom from arbitrary detention,
  Peace and Social Justice;Asia
  Criminal justice, Administration of -- China; Human rights -- China
- Proposed grant activities of the Ford Foundation to support accountable and responsive government in India (Reports 016058), 2000 (Box 821, Reel R-9315)
  Civil society -- India; Political planning -- India; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation
- Grant activities for responsive administration in India (Reports 016059), 2000 (Box 821, Reel R-9315)
  Civil society -- India; Public administration -- India; Political planning -- India; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation
- Job creation in Germany, Belgium and Sweden, 1992/ Kelleen Worden and Wayne Vroman (Reports 016060) (Box 821, Reel R-9315)
  Job creation -- Belgium; Job creation -- Germany; Job creation -- Sweden
- Welfare reform: The Family Support Act in historical context (Reports 016061), 1993 (Box 821, Reel R-9315)
  This report compares the Aid to Dependent Children (AFDC) program to the Family Support Act of 1988 (FSA).
  Project report / Urban Institute;Project report (Urban Institute)
  Federal aid to child welfare -- United States; Child support -- Law and legislation -- United States; Public welfare -- Law and legislation -- United States; Family policy -- United States
- Progressive Religion and Values Working Group papers (Reports 016062), 2004 (Box 821, Reel R-9315)
  Goals and focus of the group are discussed.
  Freedom of religion -- Study and teaching; Multiculturalism -- Study and teaching; Toleration -- Study and teaching
- The Macroeconomy and the role of job creation programs in the 1990's (Reports 016063), 1992 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  'In this paper, we examine labor market and economy wide trends over the past few decades and discuss what they portend for the ability of public job creation programs to ameliorate rising unemployment.' (p. 1)
  09200122
  Job creation -- United States
- Regional programming in Africa and the Middle East (Reports 016064), 2002 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Acquaints the Officers and Trustees with the rationale, objectives, and mode of operation of proposed grant collaborations between the Africa overseas offices. These actions were formulated at the Third All-Africa Meeting in Accra, Ghana in September 2002
  Philanthropy -- Africa
- The role of the state in promiting equity and strengthening institutions of local governance (POM) (Reports 016065), 2002 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  "The new Governance program in the Beijing office builds on work previously undertaken within the Economic Security and Law and Rights programs while adapting to China's changing political, social and economic realities. the overall goal of the governance
  Political planning -- China; Local government -- China; Civil society -- China
- Redressing regional and ethnic disparities in reproductive health and strengthening social science research in sexuality and reproductive health (POM) (Reports 016066), 2002 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  "The Sexuality and Reproductive Health Portfolio is committed to promoting gender equity, advancing the sexual and reproductive rights of women and men and supporting actions to broaden and improve access to reproductive health.. Despite the mobilization
  Progarm Officer Memo;POM
  Reproductive health -- Research -- Brazil; Medical care -- Research -- Brazil; Health services accessibility -- Brazil; Hygiene, Sexual -- Brazil; Medical policy -- Brazil; Social sciences -- Research -- Brazil
- Innovative Practices of Women Leaders for Social Change: A "Sounding" of Exemplary Women Leaders Nominated by Ford Program Staff (Reports 016067), 2002 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Peace and Social Justice;KC&F;Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS);Mexico
  Feminism; Social change
- Knowledge, creativity and freedom program: Advancing achievement and understanding (Reports 016068), 2002 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Outlines the Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom program's focus in the areas of Education and Scholarship, Sexuality and Reproductive Health, Religion, Society and Culture, Media and Arts and Culture.
  Philanthropy -- Worldwide
- Building a Constituency to Make Education Work (POM), October 30 (Reports 016069), 2002 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Education, Media Arts and Culture -- Education Reforms.
  Educational reform -- Philippines
- Strengthening scholarship on race, gender and indentity and diversity, inclusion and institutional change (POM) (Reports 016070), 2002 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Field: Education and Scholarship. Initiatives: Strengthening Scholarship on Race, Gender and Identity -- Diversity, Inclusion and Institutional Change
  Education, Sexuality, and Religion
  Program officer Memo;POM
  Educational reform -- United States; Multiculturalism
- Noncustodial fathers and their child support payments: Why do they pay so little, Oct. (Reports 016071), 1995 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Absentee fathers -- United States; Absentee fathers -- United States -- Economic conditions; Child support -- United States
- Employment equity at UCT produced by the Equal Opportunity Research Project; sponsored by the Ford Foundation (Reports 016072), 1993 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Education and Culture; Africa and the Middle East/SAN
  09101032
  The University of Cape Town Fund, Inc.
  Discrimination in employment -- South Africa -- Cape Town; Pay equity -- South Africa -- Cape Town; Discrimination in employment -- South Africa -- Cape Town -- Statistics; Pay equity -- South Africa -- Cape Town -- Statistics
- The innovations in government programs: Documentation, evaluation and dissemination, April 14 (Reports 016073), 1998 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Report on ways in which the Innovations in Government program can create common documentary procedures.
  Development leadership; Evaluation research (Social action programs)
- Constitutionalism and the containment of a disengaged military: Lessons from Africa (Reports 016074), 2000 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  "Study is concerned with ways in which some African states have tried to anticipate military intervention and how they have used constitutional mechanisms to map out new directions in Africa's political space to keep the military out of power" (Introducti
  Military reform -- Africa
- Paper for Binghamton conference: The Ford Foundation's transatlantic roles and purposes, 1951 (Reports 016075), 1999 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Biographical sketch of Fernand Braudel and the Ford Foundation's role in behavioral science research and study in France.
  Peace and Social Justice/Office of the Vice President
  Fernand Braudel and USA: Interlocuters Valuables (1999: Binghamton (N.Y.)
  Psychology -- Study and teaching; Social sciences -- Study and teaching; Sociologists
- Africa Foundations Learning Group: meeting notes, February 8 - 11 (Reports 016076), 1999 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Africa Foundations Learning Group (1999: Dakar, Senegal)
  Philanthropy -- Africa -- Congresses; Endowments -- Africa -- Congresses; Multiculturalism -- Africa
- Meta-advice at handing over (Reports 016077), 1988 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Notes prepared by Bret Wallach for the future Ford Foundation representative in Sudan, with history of the region and Ford's presence there, summary of programming, and personal (and confidential) opinions on the nature of bureaucracy and the Ford's role
  Developing Countries Program/Middle East and North Africa
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Office management -- Sudan
- Shared challenges in sexual and reproductive rights advocacy in the region Santiago, Chile, conference, June 14 -16 (Reports 016078), 1999 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Conference held in Santiago, Chile, on strategies for supporting NGOs and other actors in building comprehensive approaches to policies related to health and reproductive rights.
  Shared challenges in sexual and reproductive rights and advocacy in the region (1999: Santiago, Chile)
  Reproductive health -- Andes Region -- Congresses; Reproductive health -- Southern Cone of South America -- Congresses; Human rights advocacy
- Some thoughts upon national educational television (Reports 016079), 1977 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Public Broadcasting
  Public television -- United States; Educational television programs -- United States; Television programs, Public service -- United States; Television -- Social aspects -- United States
- Chart of Ford Foundation funding of GL grants, June 14 (Reports 016080), 2002 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  A listing of Ford Foundation grants to funders of gay, lesbian, bi-sexual and transgender issues worldwide.[…]Included in the documentation are two articles: Barriers to foundation funding of gay organizations: Evidence from Massachusetts / Stephen A. Magnus [taken from the Journal of Homosexuality, Vol. 42 (2), 2001] -- Do gay, lesbian, and bisexual oganizatio
  Gay rights; Sexual orientation; HIV (Viruses); AIDS (Disease); Gay youth; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations
- Remarks for the October 19 Kennan Center conference on the history of Soviet studies: Early Soviet studies as seen from the SSRC, October 2 (Reports 016081), 2000 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Paper presented by Francis Sutton at the Kennan Institute on the topic of Soviet studies on October 19, 2000.
  History of Soviet Studies (2000: Washington, D.C.)
  Sovietologists
- The U.S. Response to the Mexican Peso crisis: domestic politics and global markets (Reports 016082), 1995 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  08700708
  University of Maryland Foundation, Inc.
  1995 Working paper
  International economic relations -- United States; International economic relations -- Mexico
- United States relations with India and Pakistan after the Cold War: An overview of changing perceptions and policies (Reports 016083), 1995 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Research paper on international relations between the United States and India and Pakistan after the Cold War.[…]Maryland seminar on U.S. foreign policymaking.
  1995 Working Paper No. 1
  Cold War -- Influence; International relations
- NATO expansion eastward: U.S. and Russian views (Reports 016084), 1995 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Foreign relations -- United States; Foreign relations -- Russia (Federation); North Atlantic Treaty Organization -- Armed Forces
- Terms of endearment: The United States' China policy and China's accession to the World Trade Organization (Reports 016085), 1995 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  International economic relations -- United States; International economic relations -- China
- America and Europe: common challenges in a changing world (Reports 016086), 1995 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  "With the end of the Cold War, the collapse of communism and the disappearance of the Soviet Union, Europe has become both a safer place and a more unstable one. The United States and Europe no longer face the imminent threat of large scale soviet aggress
  The University of Maryland Foundation, Inc.
  Provide foreign scholars, primarily from developing world, with an analytic and practical understanding of U.S. foreign policymaking.
  Maryland Seminar on U.S. Foreign Polycymaking, 1995 working paper: no. 6
  National security -- United States; National security -- Europe; Security, International; Free trade; International trade; International relations
- U.S. foreign policy and Croatia, 1990-1995 (Reports 016087) (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Maryland Seminar on U.S. Foreign Policymaking, 1995 working paper: no. 7
  National security -- United States--National security -- Croatia; Security, International; International relations
- U.S. response to terrorism in South Asia (Reports 016088), 1995 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Maryland Seminar on U.S. Foreign Policymaking, 1995 working paper: no. 8
  Terrorism -- South Asia; National security -- South Asia; Security, International; International relations
- The challenges and limits of U.S. foreign policy in Europe: a case study of the separation process in the former Czechoslovakia (Reports 016089), 1995 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Maryland Seminar on U.S. Foreign Policymaking, 1995 working paper: no. 9
  National security -- United States; International relations; Security, International
- America - Africa: forging a new contract (Reports 016090), 1995 (Box 822, Reel R-9315)
  Provide foreign scholars, primarly from developing world, with an analytic and practical understanding of U.S. foreign policymaking.
  Maryland Seminar on U.S. Foreign Policymaking, 1995 working paper: no. 10
  International relations; International economic relations
- Whatever it takes': Community organizing responds to a changing political environment (Reports 016091), 1998 (Box 823, Reel R-9315)